AMEDEO SCIPPACERCOLA

33 Faringford Road E14 4DP, London Mobile: +44 (0)742 82 85 315 e-mail: scippacercola@gmail.com

Bachelor and MSc 1st hons degree in Engineering at "Politecnico di Milano", with previous experiences as a trader in Banca IMI and as a salestrader in JP Morgan, currently intern at Société Générale in London and Part Time student (weekends lectures) a third degree in Finance at London School of Economics.

EDUCATION

London School of Economics and Political Science

Jun 2014

MSc Finance class part-time of 2011, expected distinction

London, UK

Politecnico Di Milano (BEng and Master of Science)

Dec 2011

MSc and BEng Management, Economics and Industrial Eng. Grade: 1st class (hons.)

Milan, Italy

Over 5 years, out of a pool of 874 only 41 students graduated cum laude

High School at "Jacopo Sannazaro"

Grade: 100 cum laude Jul 2005

A-levels in classical studies: ancient greek and latin

Naples, Italy

WORK EXPERIENCE

Société Générale-CIB, FX Derivatives Salestrading

Jul 2012-Mar 2013

Interest Rate & FX derivatives

London, UK

- Pricing of derivatives instruments
- Counterparty credit check

JP Morgan Securities, Equity Salestrading

Sep 2011-Dec 2011

Salestrader, US equity desk

Milan, Italy

- Sales coverage of Italian accounts (Fideuram, Eurizon Capital, Arca, Credit Suisse, Aletti Gestielle, Prima SGR) – IPOs & Follow on, market thoughts and trade ideas
- Report of main Italian news to London and of main US company news to Italian clients

Banca IMI, Fixed Income Trading, Derivatives Desk

Mar 2011-Aug 2011

Trader, swap and inflation rate desk

Milan, Italy

- Interest rate swap pricing activity with Murex
- Deal execution
- Hedging and portfolio management activity

IT SKILLS

OS: Windows, Mac OS X Leopard, Linux

Data mining software:

E-views, STATISTICA,

Office package:

ECDL Advanced

SAS EM, SPSS

Financial Analysis: Bloomberg, Reuters

Web developing software: Adobe CS5

Languages:

VBA, C++, Html, Xml CMS:

Joomla, Mambo, Drupal

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Course in Advanced Econometrics, London School of Economics

Jun 2010-Aug 2010

Econometric analysis, Time series, Macro econometrics, Micro econometrics

London, UK

High School President, Liceo Classico J. Sannazaro

Jun 2008-Aug 2008

1073 votes received over 1260 Students

Naples, Italy

LANGUAGES

Italian: Native

English: Fluent (IELTS 7.5, TOEIC 870, TOEFL 660)

Nov 2008 -Feb 2008

Cambridge University, Saint John's College Ef School of English

Cambridge, UK

HOBBIES & OTHER CERTIFICATES

Sports: Captain of "Circolo Cannottieri Naples" Sailing team, Skiing and Tennis **Music:** Piano, Guitar **Other hobbies:** Italian and Ancient Literature, SEO

GRE Certificate: 770 (95 percentile)